hey everybody welcome to this a2
english listening practice video you can
use this video to practice your
listening
and comprehension as i speak before we
start
remember to subscribe to the channel
click on the bell
and follow us on instagram you ready so
today
i'm gonna talk about high school i think
this is an
interesting topic to discuss because
high school
is different in different countries in
today's video
we'll focus on high school in america
first let's talk a little bit about the
structure of high school in america
most high schools in the country include
9th 10th 11th and 12th grade
before students start high school they
attend elementary school first
and then middle school second high
school is like
the third level of education so let me
teach you some important words we use
to label each year of high school people
in their first year of high school ninth
grade
are called freshmen people in 10th grade
are called sophomores 11th graders
are called juniors and 12th graders
are called seniors these words are
important to learn
because this is how native speakers
refer
to different years of high school so
during each school year there are two
separate semesters
normally the first semester lasts from
the end of summer
to the beginning of winter then the
second semester
starts at the beginning of the new year
and
continues on until the end of spring
in the traditional school system
students have a
long summer vacation at the end of the
school year
however nowadays many schools have
a year-round schedule in this system
the summer break is shorter but the
other vacations
like winter break and spring break are
longer
a lot of students prefer this system
because
they would rather have more vacation
time throughout the year
instead of a really long summer break so
during each semester most students have
around six different classes for six
different subjects
in general most students take the same
or similar classes however some students
take advanced level classes we usually
call these
ap classes i had a few ap
classes during my time in high school
and they were
definitely more difficult than the
regular classes
i think the normal high school classes
in the u.s
aren't that hard many of my students
who live in other countries tell me that
their high school classes were hard
and required a lot of work how about
your high school classes
were they hard another important topic
to talk about is the quality of the
teachers
in my experience some public school
teachers are good
and some are bad honestly i don't think
i had
a lot of good teachers most of them were
average or bad in private school
the quality of the teachers is usually
better
this is probably the situation in most
countries
not just the us one question that many
people
ask me is about which foreign languages
american students study in high school
well
in the u.s most students get to choose
which language they want to study the
majority of the students choose
spanish because it's the most useful
foreign language for most americans
there are usually more spanish teachers
and classes than
any other language the second most
popular language that
students choose is french and the third
language
is probably italian i studied spanish in
high school
because i thought it would be the
easiest language to learn
okay lastly let's talk about the
importance of high school in america
students need to do well in high school
if they want to go
to a good college they need to get good
grades
and they need to do well on the sat
the sat is the exam that high school
students
take if they want to go to college
students can take this test
multiple times to try to get a good
score
i only took the sat once and i didn't
study for it
i didn't really care about going to a
good college
all right now i'm gonna ask you three
questions
about today's video to check your
comprehension
number one in the u.s what do we call
people who are in ninth grade number two
what are ap classes number three
what are the three most common languages
that
american students study okay remember to
subscribe to the channel
click on the bell and follow us on
instagram
for more english tips and lessons i'll
see you next time
[Music]
you